## **Greg Dowson**

San Rafael, CA 94901 • 415.847.7140 • gregdowson@comcast.net

## Systems Engineer & Administrator

Tech-savvy professional with extensive experience in data recovery, network management, and web development

Proven ability in conducting root cause analysis and timeliness for resolving Windows, VMware, and Linux issues, while enhancing system applications. Demonstrated record of success in troubleshooting computers, increasing efficiency, and optimizing the access and utilization of shared information. Harnesses astute analytical capabilities and perceptive operational requirements to take advantage of new, emerging and existing technology. Capable of successfully sharing complex data equally well with experts and neophytes. Lateral thinker, resolving problems right the first time.

VMware, Windows, Citrix, SCCM & Linux System Administration / System & Server Configuration / Office 365 / AWS / Azure / Desktop Support Strategies / Process Improvement / Installation & Configuration / Troubleshooting & Resolution

#### **TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES**

Languages: POWERSHELL, BASH SHELL, PERL, BATCH SCRIPTING, PYTHON, SQL, VBSCRIPT (See some of my scripts at <a href="http://github.com/gregdowson">http://github.com/gregdowson</a>

Other Applications: HP/NetApp/Tegile/EMC/Hitachi/Dell EqualLogic SAN/NAS, Veeam, Veritas-NetBackup, Qualsys, Symantec (Antivirus, SCSP, ESM, SEP), WSUS, MS Project/Access/Office 365/2016/2013, Visio, BMC Portal, Sysinternals, Tivoli, BigFix, Infoblox, DNS, DHCP, NNTP, LDAP, OKTA, Kerberos, DFSR, SMTP, SSO, SFTP, SAML, OAuth, RSA-SSL and Duo multiple factor secure login, Solaris, Big Fix, VMware Horizon VDI, SharePoint, Jira, JAMF

### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Engineering - MIS, Stanford University, California

Bachelor of Science in Engineering - Computer Systems, Stanford University, California

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Sr. Systems Engineer (2/2020 - Present)

CENTER FOR ELDERS INDEPENDENCE (CEI), Oakland

- Successfully resolved escalated helpdesk tickets regarding complex issues with Active Directory, Group Policy Management, VPN access, VOIP phones, including MDM apps (Intune, VMware Airwatch).
- ★ Wrote numerous PowerShell scripts for automating Windows system administration and alerting on clinical server-applications.
- → Impactfully resolved complex issues for 150 Windows Server 2003/2008/2012/2016 including VMWare administration (5.5, 6.0, 6.7), server hardening GPOs, server patching.
- ★ Key Lead for configuring security policies, network routing, and template scripts for Palo Alto 820/850 firewalls.
- → Built CEI's SolarWinds Network Performance Monitor system from the ground up, creating Windows 2016 Hyper-V and MS SQL database servers for monitoring, reporting, and alerting on 300 network devices/servers.
- Configured routing, port connections, for Cisco Meraki MS350 and Enterasys switches including wireless Meraki MR52 access points.
- ★ Configured updated network topology with Visio diagrams for 8 clinics including the TPX/ MPOEs, Cisco 2951, 1851, VoIP phones using Shoretel PRI SG-T1k and SG-90V, PCs, Android, IPhones, printers, and backup power Smart-UPS SRT 3000s.
- + Lead team player for developing proposed Cato Networks, VMware-Velocloud SDWAN configurations.
  - **Sr. Consulting Engineer** (7/2019 to 3/20/20)

QUEST TECHNOLOGY MANAGEMENT, Roseville

→ Methodically deployed and administered a 50-cluster VMware 6.7 ESX infrastructure with Windows 2016 domain controllers, Active Directory, and Group Policy and related PowerShell scripting for automating tasks.

# **Greg Dowson**

- Configured Azure Active Directory Domain Services (Azure AD DS) for automating updates to Office 365, Exchange and Windows servers. Configured Azure Active Directory Domain Services (Azure AD DS) for automating updates to Office 365, Exchange and Windows servers.
- → Deployed 10 ESX clusters in Azure with excellent client feedback. Configured and updated the Azure infrastructure using Terraform 12.18 with team collaboration and approval for changes.
- → Deployed patches and software upgrades to 200 desktops using SCCM.
- ◆ Supported and architected core IT services such as Windows Servers, virtualization, Active Directory, file and print sharing, Office 365, SharePoint online, FTP, backups, security and network infrastructure.
- → Project Managed successful Citrix XenApp/XenDesktop upgrade from 6.5 to 7.15, publishing applications, desktops, and configuring XA/XD Service in Citrix Cloud.

## Sr. Systems Engineer (10/2017 - 6/2019)

#### UNIVERSITY OF SAN FRANCISCO, San Francisco

- ★ Methodically executed SQL server administration, including developing failover clusters and availability groups under Windows 2012 and 2016 server operating systems.
- ★ Leveraged astute capabilities during the development, configuration, and migration of a 200-server VMware farm to a VMware 6.7 Virtual Center Server Appliance (VCSA) and ESXi 6.7 hosts with single sign on, exceeding expectations on quality implementation time.
- → Utilized technical acumen for configuring a 50 VDA Citrix farm (XenDesktop), providing remote Windows 10 desktops to 200 users. Regarded as a core member in performing a holistic Linux system administration for the VCSA and ESXi 6.7 hosts.
- Wrote and revised PowerShell scripts for populating user and group information for 20,000 AD accounts.
- → Developed GPOs, numerous PowerShell and Shell scripts and scheduled tasks for Citrix, Active Directory, ADFS and VMware.
- + Configured PTR system monitoring, Netwrix 9.8 for server audit monitoring and NetBackup 8.1.2 for backups to tape libraries and Hitachi-Tegile storage.
- + Championed Group Policy changes using Quest GPO admin and administering Quest Recovery Manager.
- ★ Configured backups for Active Directory data and restores.
- ★ Received excellent feedback for resolving Duo issues.
- → Managed the configuration and administration of 300 servers and 2500 PC/Mac for DNS/DHCP connections, cloud storage, AD, ADCS-CA Certificates, PKI, Kerberos authentication, IIS web sites.
- + Achieved maximum level of customer satisfaction and retention regarding Windows 10, MACs, Solaris, AD group and user access, ADCS and Windows 2008, 2012, and 2016 and Concord Document System by promptly resolving trouble tickets.

## **Sr. System Administrator** (2/2016 – 9/2017)

#### NATIONAL MORTGAGE INSURANCE. Emervville

- → Delivered exceptional tier 2 and 3 help desk support, while escalating and resolving issues for Windows 7/10 and Mac.
- ◆ Leveraged key technical skills in developing GPOs, SolarWinds monitoring, PowerShell scripts, active directory components, AD migration, Azure AD and security on Windows Server 2008, 2012, 2016.
- + Ensured the migration of Citrix Farm to Windows Server 2012. Regarded as an administrator for Jira issue tracking nearly 100 financial software issues.
- ★ Steered efforts towards maintaining all office desktop applications, including Office 365/2013/2016, SCCM 2012, MDT, Intune, SharePoint 2013, MDM, 0365-Exchange, Skype, to high customer satisfaction.
- ★ Fostered robust relationships with users and management regarding Change Management, Incident Management, troubleshooting, and migration.
- + Played a vital role in designing, implementing, and maintaining a 30 server Citrix Windows 2008 Farm using VMware 6.0, Citrix Provisioning, Director, Studio-Storefront, NetScaler, VDI, XenApp, XenDesktop, XenMobile (Citrix Endpoint Management).
- ★ Team Lead migrating 30 VMs to AWS Amazon EC2 using AWS Connector for vCenter successfully with quick issue resolution.
- ◆ Commended for building and managing an RSA appliance and troubleshooting RSA issues for dual sign in.
- ★ Commended by senior management for outstanding performance in configuring JAMF Pro for apple devices, Mac OS and Splunk for NIST cyber security compliance, including AWS, Azure cloud services, Azure AD Connect, DirSync.
- → Devised and crafted numerous scripts and upgraded Quest Change Auditor to 5.5 to efficiently document SOX compliance, exceeding auditor and information security expectations with swift issue resolution.

## Operating Systems Engineer (4/2015 - 1/2016)

IBM | WELLS FARGO BANK, San Francisco

★ Architected and deployed an on-premise Azure Cloud system (IAAS/PAAS), including SCOM/VMM, Hyper-V, cluster server configuration with administrative and tenant portals, and service templates.

# **Greg Dowson**

- → Spearheaded project operations from initial to completion state ahead of schedule and under budget. Deployed and administered VMs, including Windows 2012 servers, SQL servers and clusters.
- ◆ Built and configured vCenter on multiple sites including vMotion, storage, HA, DRS, PowerCLI scripts and SQL databases.
- ★ Lead VMware operations engineer and Windows system administrator for quickly resolving complex VMware, Windows and related network issues, including Active Directory, system firewalling, GPOs.
- + Championed launch of several OEM products and releases encompassing both hard drives and tape drives. Configured Big Fix to patch 320 servers ensuring security compliance using QRadar.

### **Sr. System Administrator** (4/2014 - 4/2015)

AUTODESK, San Rafael

- + Strategic, operations authority over SCCM administration, OSD task sequences, MDT, MDM, software deployment, patching, and SQL reports for PCs and servers
- → Tackled significant challenges during overseeing a 2400 VM datacenter, including server builds, vCenter converter, VMotion, DRS, HA, PowerCLI scripts, SRM, configuring ESXi and Cisco UCS physical servers.
- Provided high quality support and configuration for Hyper-V, Citrix, VDI, EMC SAN, SCOM, PXE, Exchange 2007/2010/2013, MS SQL servers
- Devised and proposed disaster recovery plans and ran disaster recovery testing using SRM for 100 production VMs.
- ★ Recognized as a lead engineer for migrating 650 Windows 2003 servers to Windows 2008/2012 VMware.
- → Successfully managed and configured the migration of 20 SCCM 2007 servers to SCCM 2012.

#### **Sr. System Administrator** (2/2009 – 3/2014)

LESCONCIERGES | US FEDERAL RESERVE BANK, San Francisco

- Managed, upgraded, and diagnosed the 42 Linux and 110 Windows 2008 servers.
- ★ Wrote and administered rigorous and demanding PowerShell, Linux shell, Perl and cron job scripts to automate tasks, alerts, data feeds and encryption.
- ◆ Performed and configured eVault server backups and recommended disaster recovery plans.
- + Formed and organized infrastructure documentation, and adherence of PCI security compliance.
- Migrated to Windows 2012 domain controllers, including Active Directory, GPOs, DNS, and DHCP administration.
- Engineered and administered Hyper-V, Citrix, VDI, EMC SAN, SCOM, PXE, Exchange 2007/2010/2013, MS SQL.
- ◆ Configured Dell PowerVault, EqualLogic SAN, Dell servers, Cisco 2150 routers, VPNs, Meraki firewalls, Cisco Catalyst 3750 switches, ASA 5500, PDUs, Cisco wireless APs, Cisco VoIP phones, Apple OSX servers.
- Built and maintained 63 Windows 2008 VMware servers, Windows 7/8 PCs, and networking for Shanghai office.
- → Monitored all the aspects of engineering operations, while mitigating and resolving complex issues, including ESXi networking, VM backups, and recovery.
- Boosted the reputation of the IT support division and enhanced server operations through innovations that included clustering servers and structuring VMware operations and backups (VDR).
- → Succeeded in automating server administration operations by conceptualizing and building Bash, VBScript, PowerShell, and batch executables.

#### Additional Experience:

- Sr. System Administrator, NEKTAR THERAPEUTICS, South San Francisco
- Sr. System Administrator, NOVARTIS-VACCINES, Emeryville

Supervisor - Computer Information and Telecommunications, PACIFIC GAS AND ELECTRIC, San Francisco

#### CERTIFICATIONS

MS Certified Systems Engineer (MCSE 2012)

MS Certified Technical Specialist (MCTS-SCCM 2012)

Oracle Certified Professional (OCP 2012)

Oracle Certified Master DBA (2012)

MS Certified Database Administrator (MCDBA)

MS Certified Professional + Internet (MCP+I)

MS Certified Professional (MCP)

Certified Cisco Network Administrator (CCNA 2005-2008)

Network Security Specialist Certificate

Project Management Program (PMP) Certificate

Citrix Certified Administrator (CCA)